# **HECTOR LUIS REYES PUPO**

hlpupo@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/hlpupo github.com/hlpupo hlpupo, github.io 1750W 56th ST, Hialeah, FL, 33012 (786) 372 4254

Computer Sciences Engineer with more than 9 years of experience as software developer. Adaptable to different environments, teamwork experience and under pressure. He is characterized by rapid learning, self-improvement, follow good programming practices and techniques. Proficient full life cycle of the software development process.

#### **Technical Skills**

- Languages: PHP, JavaScript, Ruby, NodeJS
- Frameworks & Tools: Symfony, Laravel, Codeigniter, PHPUnit, Doctrine, Eloquent, Ruby and Rails, AngularJS, ReactJS, jQuery, BackboneJS, EmberJS, RequireJS, Express, Bootstrap, Sass, Less, Angular Material, Polymer, Composer, NPM, Bower, Gulp, Ionic, Cordova, Karma, Jasmine, Nuxeo Platform, Elastic Search.
- Databases: MySQL, PostgreSQL, Microsoft SQL Server, MongoDB, Redis, Firebase.
- Development Resources: LAMP, OOP, ORM, RESTful API, Web Services, Twig, Blade, AJAX, JSON, UML, Dependency Injection, Test Driven Development(TDD)
- Server Technology: Apache, Nginx, Azure, Amazon AWS.
- IDEs: PhpStorm, WebStorm.
- Version Control & Project Tracking: Git, Jira, Confluence, Trello, Redmine
- Agile Development: Scrum, Extreme Programming(XP), RUP
- Operating System: OS X, Linux, Microsoft Windows,

## **Professional Experience**

# Full Stack Developer at Globant, Montevideo, Uruguay

April. 2015 - August. 2016

Full stack developer

- Developing solutions for a client in the United States (Company GREY).
- Working on 3 project for the same company.
- Designed software solution to implement RESTful services.
- Wrote maintainable and extensible code in a team environment.
- Modified existing software to correct errors, upgrade interfaces and improve performance.
- Suggesting improvements on design and functionality.

#### **COMPUTER SCIENCES UNIVERSITY (UCI), La Habana, Cuba**

Dec. 2014 – March. 2015

Project manager, lead architect

- Development of a framework for developing multimedia software with free and open source software technologies
- Software developer working in a 4 member team (2 software developers, 1 software tester and 1 project manager).

#### **COMPUTER SCIENCES UNIVERSITY (UCI), La Habana, Cuba**

Sept. 2014 - Dec. 2014

Architect, Developer

- Development of a demo for Android platform of the collection of educational software "El Navegante".
- Leader of a team of 5 developers.

## **COMPUTER SCIENCES UNIVERSITY (UCI), La Habana, Cuba**

Jan. 2013 - Oct. 2014

Leader of application modules, Developer

Development of a platform for managing educational games "Pointer".

### **COMPUTER SCIENCES UNIVERSITY (UCI), La Habana, Cuba**

Oct. 2011 - May. 2014

Software Architect, Project Manager, Database Designer, Developer

- Project Manager and Architect, working on the development of two tools, one for management and administration of content (Backend) and one for the visualization and interaction (Frontend) with the collection "El Navegante". With a team of 20 developers. (Senior, Intermediate and Trainers).
- All the projects were delivered on time, with all the required features implemented, using the most modern technologies and frameworks.
- Work on designing the database.
- Responsible for the development of two application modules.
- Responsible for the architecture design.

# COMPUTER SCIENCES UNIVERSITY (UCI), La Habana, Cuba

Sept. 2010 - May. 2011

Software Developer

Frontend and backend developer for different collections of educational software.

# COMPUTER SCIENCES UNIVERSITY (UCI), La Habana, Cuba

Sept. 2007 - Jul. 2009

Trainee

- Working with Senior Developers in the development of Educational Games
- I worked in the development of various educational games to be incorporated in the collection of educational software named Multisaber, supported by Ministry of Education in Cuba (MINED).

#### Education

**COMPUTER SCIENCES UNIVERSITY (UCI)**, La Habana, Cuba Engineer in Computer Science.

Sept. 2005 – Jul. 2010

#### References

Eitan Zadok, Director at Global Solution Delivery GREY - <u>eitan.zadok@grey.com</u> (W+1 212 546 2553 M +1 516 974 2692)

Juan Martín Obes, Śr. Project Manager at Globant - <u>jobesz@gmail.com</u> (646 874 4196) Pablo Silva, Sr. Project Manager at Globant - <u>pablo.silva@globant.com</u>